Gross, James Additional NLRB Research Audio-Visual Materials /4166 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James Gross Additional NLRB Research Audio-Visual Materials
1984-1990
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gross, James
/4166 AV
13.33 cubic feet
13.3 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
Audio recordings of Prof. Jim Gross's interviews used when he was doing research on the NLRB
8272531
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 22, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
James Gross (1933-) was raised near Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He graduated from La Salle University with a Bachelor of Science in 1956. Gross received his Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1962.
He taught as an assistant professor at Holy Cross College from 1960 to 1966 before joining the faculty at Cornell. He was named an associate professor in 1968 and a full professor in 1975.
Gross's three-volume history of the National Labor Relations Board has been called both authoritative and exhaustive. The Reshaping of the National Labor Relations Board: National Labor Policy in Transition, 1937-1947, the second volume of his trilogy, won the Philip Taft Labor History Book Award in 1983.
He is a member of the National Academy of Arbitrators, the American Arbitration Associaiton, and the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service.
Gross received a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities, and in 2007 was Fulbright Visiting Research Chair in Corporate Social Responsibility at McGill University in Canada.
Biographical / Historical
NLRB 1935-2010
The National Labor Relations Board is proud of its 75-year history of enforcing the National Labor Relations Act, the primary law governing relations between employers and employees in the private sector. On July 5, 1935, President Franklin Roosevelt signed the Act into law, stating that the law sought to achieve "common justice and economic advance." Starting in the Great Depression and continuing through World War II and the economic growth and challenges that followed, the NLRB has worked to guarantee the rights of employees to bargain collectively, if they choose to do so.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4057: James Gross NLRB Files /4057 AV: James Gross NLRB Audiocassettes /4057 P: James Gross NLRB Photographs /4124: James Gross Papers, Additional NLRB Research Files /4232: James Gross Collection of NLRB 60th Annual Conference Files /4186: James Gross Additional Research Files /4190: James Gross Additional Research Files 5697: James A. Gross Arbitration Files 5959: James Gross Additional Arbitration Files /4079: James Gross Additional Files /4166: James Gross Additional NLRB Research Files
Gross, James A., 1933-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.; United States National Labor Relations Board.
8272531
- Arnold Ordman (Box 1.1)
  - Arnold Ordman - tapes 1-4 (Box 1)
- Arnold Ordman (Box 1.2)
- Arnold Ordman (Box 1.3)
- Arnold Ordman (Box 1.4)
- Stanley Strauss - tape 1 (Box 2.1)
  - Stanley Strauss - tapes 1-3,5 (Box 2)
- Stanley Strauss - tape 2 (Box 2.2)
- Stanley Strauss - tape 3 (Box 2.3)
- Stanley Strauss - tape 5 (Box 2.4)
- George Bott (Box 3.1)
  - George Bott - tapes 1-7 (Box 3)
- George Bott (Box 3.2)
- George Bott (Box 3.3)
- George Bott (Box 3.4)
- George Bott (Box 3.5)
- George Bott (Box 3.6)
- George Bott (Box 3.7)
- John Truesdale (Box 4.1)
  - John Truesdale - tapes 1-3 (Box 4)
- John Truesdale (Box 4.2)
- John Truesdale (Box 4.3)
- Soutar (11/16/1990) (Box 5.1)
  - Soutar (11/16/1990) - tapes 1-3 (Box 5)
- Soutar (11/16/1990) (Box 5.2)
- Soutar (11/16/1990) (Box 5.3)
- John Higgins (Box 6.1)
  - John Higgins - tapes 1-2 (Box 6)
- John Higgins (Box 6.2)
- Gross (9/27/1982) (Box 7.1)
  - Gross, 201, Lecture Notes (9/16/1985) - tapes 1-2 (Box 7)
- Gross (9/27/1982) (Box 7.2)
- Thomas N. Kessel (9/1989) - 1 tape (Box 8)
  - Thomas N. Kessel (9/1989) - tape 1 (Box 8)
- Roman Pucinski (Box 9.1)
  - Roman Pucinski - tape 1-2 (Box 9)
- Roman Pucinski (Box 9.2)
- Mallet-Prevost (Box 10.1)
  - Mallet-Prevost - tapes 1-2 (Box 10)
- Mallet-Prevost (Box 10.2)
- Stephan Gordon (Box 11.1)
  - Stephen Gordon - 5 tapes (Box 11)
- Stephan Gordon (Box 11.2)
- Stephan Gordon (Box 11.3)
- Stephan Gordon (Box 11.4)
- Stephan Gordon (Box 11.5)
- Lester Asher (Box 12.1)
  - Lester Asher - 3 tapes (Box 12)
- Lester Asher (Box 12.2)
- Lester Asher (Box 12.3)
- A mock arbitration - 1 tape (Box 13)
  - A mock arbitration - 1 tape (Box 13)
- Howard Jenkins - tape 1 (Box 14.1)
  - Howard Jenkins - tapes 1-4 (Box 14)
- Howard Jenkins - tape 2 (Box 14.2)
- Howard Jenkins - tape 3 (Box 14.3)
- Howard Jenkins - tape 4 (Box 14.4)
- Norton Come - tape 1 (Box 15.1)
  - Norton Come - tapes 1-10 (Box 15)
- Norton Come - tape 2 (Box 15.10)
- Norton Come - tape 3 (Box 15.2)
- Norton Come - tape 4 (Box 15.3)
- Norton Come - tape 5 (Box 15.4)
- Norton Come - tape 6 (Box 15.5)
- Norton Come - tape 7 (Box 15.6)
- Norton Come - tape 8 (Box 15.7)
- Norton Come - tape 9 (Box 15.8)
- Norton Come - tape 10 (Box 15.9)
- Peter Nash - tape 1 (Box 16.1)
  - Peter Nash - tapes 1-5 (Box 16)
- Peter Nash - tape 2 (Box 16.2)
- Peter Nash - tape 3 (Box 16.3)
- Peter Nash - tape 4 (Box 16.4)
- Peter Nash - tape 5 (Box 16.5)
- Frank Kleiler (Box 17.1)
  - Frank Kleiler - tapes 1-3 (Box 17)
- Frank Kleiler (Box 17.2)
- Frank Kleiler (Box 17.3)
- Mozart Ratner (Box 18.1)
  - Mozart Ratner - tapes 1-3 (Box 18)
- Mozart Ratner (Box 18.2)
- Mozart Ratner (Box 18.3)
- A. Norman Somers (Box 19.1)
  - A. Norman Somers - tapes 1-3 (Box 19)
- A. Norman Somers (Box 19.2)
- A. Norman Somers (Box 19.3)
- Warren Davidson (Box 20.1)
  - Warren Davidson - tapes 1-6 (Box 20)
- Warren Davidson (Box 20.2)
- Warren Davidson (Box 20.3)
- Warren Davidson (Box 20.4)
- Warren Davidson (Box 20.5)
- Warren Davidson (Box 20.6)
- 10/22/1984 - tape 1 (Box 21.1)
  - 10/22/1984 - tapes 1-4 (Box 21)
- 10/22/1984 - tape 2 (Box 21.2)
- 10/22/1984 - tape 3 (Box 21.3)
- 10/22/1984 - tape 4 (Box 21.4)
- Michael Walsh - tape 1 (Box 22.1)
  - Michael Walsh - tapes 1-2 (Box 22)
- Michael Walsh - tape 2 (Box 222)
- Ralph Winkler - tape 1 (Box 23.1)
  - Ralph Winkler - tapes 1-2 (Box 23)
- Ralph Winkler - tape 2 (Box 23.2)
- Guy Farmer - tapes 1 [tape 1 is broken] (Box 24.1)
  - Guy Farmer - tapes 1-3 [tape 1 is broken] (Box 24)
- Guy Farmer - tape 2 (Box 24.2)
- Guy Farmer - tape 3 (Box 24.3)
- Wm. Feldesman - tape 1 (Box 25.1)
  - Wm. Feldesman - tapes 1-4 (Box 25)
- Wm. Feldesman - tape 2 (Box 25.2)
- Wm. Feldesman - tape 3 (Box 25.3)
- Wm. Feldesman - tape 4 (Box 25.4)
- Sam Zagoria - tape 1 (Box 26.1)
  - Sam Zagoria - tapes 1-4 (Box 26)
- Sam Zagoria - tape 2 (Box 26.2)
- Sam Zagoria - tape 3 (Box 26.3)
- Sam Zagoria - tape 4 (Box 26.4)
- Ted Kammholz - tape 1 (Box 27.1)
  - Ted Kammholz - tapes 1-2 (Box 27)
- Ted Kammholz - tape 2 (Box 27.2)
- Farmer Interview, by Shelley Coppock - tape 1 (Box 28.1)
  - Farmer Interview, by Shelley Coppock - tapes 1-3 (Box 28)
- Farmer Interview, by Shelley Coppock - tape 2 (Box 28.2)
- Farmer Interview, by Shelley Coppock - tape 3 (Box 28.3)
- John Farming - 10/6/1984 - tape 1 (Box 29.1)
  - John Farming - 10/6/1984 - tapes 1-4 (Box 29)
- John Farming - 10/6/1984 - tape 2 (Box 29.2)
- John Farming - 10/6/1984 - tape 3 (Box 29.3)
- John Farming - 10/6/1984 - tape 4 (Box 29.4)
- NLRB - 10/22-23/1984 - tapes 3 (Box 30.1)
  - NLRB - 10/22-23/1984 - tapes 3,4 (Box 30)
- NLRB - 10/22-23/1984 - tapes 4 (Box 30.2)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.1)
  - J. Gross, NLRB History - tapes 1-7 (Box 31)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.2)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.3)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.4)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.5)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.6)
- J. Gross, NLRB History (Box 31.7)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 32)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 32)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 33)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 33)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 34)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 34)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 35)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 35)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 36)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 36)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 37)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 37)
- Unlabeled - tapes 1-3 [appeared to go together] (Box 38.1)
  - Unlabeled - tapes 1-3 [appeared to go together] (Box 38)
- Unlabeled - tapes 1-3 [appeared to go together] (Box 38.2)
- Unlabeled - tapes 1-3 [appeared to go together] (Box 38.3)
- Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 39)
  - Unlabeled - 1 tape (Box 39)
- Audio digitized from the collection. (Box 40)